[Music]
I want to invite you uh as we're
beginning to just hit that share button
um let people know uh to tune into this
message because I believe this message
is going to be a lifechanging message as
have the messages that I've been
preaching previously in the last five or
six
weeks this is a continuation of this
series on the theme of justification by
faith and um
if you saw the the title The Valley Of
The Shadow you probably
automatically knew the psalm that we
would be addressing today put a one in
the chat if you know the psalm if you
know the
psalm the very well-known
Psalm that speaks of the Valley of the
Shadow let's go to it let's go to it it
is PSAL PM 23 a Psalm that is uh perhaps
the most wellknown
Psalm in all the Bible uh it is a Psalm
that that people reach for when they are
going through times of trouble let's go
to the
screen Psalm
23 beginning with verse one the Bible
says the Lord is my shepherd I shall not
want he maketh me to lie down in Green
Pastures he leadth me beside Still
Waters he restoreth my
soul he leadth me in the paths of
righteousness for his name's
sake yay though I walk through the
valley of the shadow of death I will
fear no evil for thou art with me thy
rod and thy staff they comfort me verse
five thou preparest a
table before me in the presence of my
enemies thou anointest my head with oil
my cup runneth over
surely goodness and mercy shall follow
me all the days of my life and I will
dwell in the house of the Lord
Forever This psalm
is a Psalm about God's leading how many
of you want God leading in your life put
a one in the chat if you want God
leading in your life this is a
Psalm that that speaks to God's leading
in our lives but as we think about this
Psalm on a little deeper level which
we're going to be doing throughout this
entire sermon we we we get the greatest
picture of God's
leading in the Old Testament in fact we
get the we get the greatest picture of
God's leading uh uh the greatest story
of God's leading is how he led the
children of Israel out of Egypt into the
promised
land a and in Deuteronomy chapter 8
there's a very interesting way that this
leading is phrased notice with me
Deuteronomy
8:15 speaking of the Lord who led thee
through that great and terrible
Wilderness wherein were fiery serpents
and scorpions and drought where there
was no water who brought thee forth out
of the rock or who brought thee forth
water out of the rock who fed thee in
the wilderness with Mana which thy
fathers knew not that he might humble
thee and that he might prove thee to do
thee good at thy latter end note with me
how the Wilderness is described as that
great terrible Wilderness wherein were
fiery serpents and scorpions and drought
and no water almost as if the Bible here
is describing the Wilderness as this I
don't know kind of like a
valley of a shadow of
death note with me note with me in fact
in Jeremiah CH 2 and verse 6 the Bible
literally says this neither said they
where is the Lord that brought us up out
of the land of Egypt that led us through
the Wilderness through a land of deserts
and of pits
through a kind of
drought or through a land of
drought through and of the shadow of
death through a land that no man passed
through and where no man dwelt so come
back with me for a moment and what I
want you to catch here
beloved is the fact that in Jeremiah 2
vers vers six the Bible literally
defines their
journey in the
wilderness as a land of a shadow or the
shadow of
death please note with
me that as God is leading them to Canan
they must first go through this Valley
or land
of the shadow of death if I can rephrase
that whoever desires to get to Canaan
must first go through the valley of the
shadow of death put a one in the chat if
you are following what I'm saying thus
far we are just looking at the
example the children of Israel going
through the Wilderness the Wilderness
itself was as it were a valley of The
Shadow of death
now you know what the psalm says yay
though I walk through the valley of the
shadow of death I will fear no evil now
why were they to fear no evil why this
is does a psalmist say I will fear no
evil put it in the chat for me
please the reason the psalmist
says I will fear no evil is because of
something very specific the verse goes
on to
say thy rod and thy staff they comfort
me all right come on y'all I will fear
no evil why thy rod and thy staff they
comfort me thy rod and thy staff they
comfort me so you might
remember
how in in The Exodus as they're making
their Journey out of Egypt the the the
staff of Moses plays a crucial part in
their
Deliverance in Exodus chapter 4 for
example the Bible says in verse two
Exodus chapter 4 and verse 2 and the
Lord said unto him what is that in thine
hand and he said a rod and he said cast
it onto the ground and he cast it onto
the ground and it became
a serpent and Moses fled from before
it and the Lord said unto Moses put
forth thine hand and take it by the tail
and he put forth his hand and caught it
and it became a rod in his hand what I
want you to understand beloved is that
when Moses is told to throw down the rod
the rod say it with me everyone the rod
becomes a what the rod becomes a serpent
you might this might be of of of of
interest to you because you might
remember that in numbers 21:9 there is
another incident with the
rod if we look at this Rod remember it
is the rod that led the that helped the
children of Israel avoid the
plagues and now in numbers 21 go with me
to the screen numbers
21 numbers 21 and verse n the Bible
says and Moses made a serpent of brass
and put it on a pole and it came to pass
that if if a serpent had bitten any man
when he beheld The Serpent of brass he
lived so then this this this Rod that
accompanied the children of Israel on
their Journey Through the Wilderness
through the valley of the shadow of
death are y'all are catching me through
the valley of the shadow of death they
were to fear no evil why because the rod
kept the plagues from them and the
rod when they were bitten by any serpent
all they had to do was to look at the
serpent on the pole on the rod on the
staff and as they looked they would
live as they looked they would live
so so so I'm setting the the foundation
here because what I want you to see
beloved is that according to 1
Corinthians chapter 10 verse 1 and2
Paul says this of this journey moreover
Brethren I would not that you should be
ignorant how that all of our fathers
were under the cloud and all passed
through the sea and were all baptized
unto Moses in the cloud and in the sea
you'll
remember that God God told Moses again
lift up the rod and the seas are going
to part so it was the rod that kept them
from the plagues it was the rod that
when lifted up allowed them to cross the
Red Sea which was certain death and it
was the rod the serpent on the
pole that kept them from dying from the
Ser from the Serpent's bites in the
wilderness y though I walk through the
valley of the sh of death I will fear no
evil why thy rod and thy staff they are
with me now now when we understand this
we begin to see a very powerful parallel
and let me lay this out for you beloved
because I am I'm going this sermon today
is designed specifically for an
appeal I'm inviting you to do something
at the end of this sermon at the end of
this message which which which is very
specific in nature some of you are
wondering Pastor how can I improve my my
prayer life how can I get closer to God
how what does it mean to let me just let
me just pause just be prepared for the
appeal the
parallel you remember when Jesus was
born that there was a death decree a a
and and as a result of this death decree
Jesus is taken into
Egypt but then in Matthew chapter 2:14
the Bible says when he arose he took the
young child and his mother by night and
departed into Egypt and was there until
the death of Herod that it might be
fulfilled which was spoken of the Lord
by the prophet saying out of Egypt have
I called my son out of Egypt have I
called my son so I need you to
understand that in this text Jesus is
being compared to Israel remember what
Moses said to is to to Egypt when when
to to Pharaoh God has said let my
firstborn go which was symbolic of
Israel but now in the New Testament
we're seeing that
Jesus is the Israel of
God and Jesus the Bible says he goes
into Egypt that it might be fulfilled
out of Egypt have I called my son so we
know that that Israel like like Israel
Jesus is reliving the history of the Old
Testament you'll remember that the
crossing of the Red Sea we just read was
like a baptism and interesting in ly
enough after Jesus comes out of Egypt
and he is grown the B the Bible
says uh in Matthew 4:1 then was Jesus
led up of the spirit Into the Wilderness
to be tempted of the devil and when he
had fasted 40 days and 40 nights he was
afterward hungry so I need yall to catch
this
below just as God brought ancient Israel
out of Egypt and then brought the them
into the
Wilderness which we understand was a
symbol of the Valley of the shadow of
death so we now see Jesus who is brought
out of Egypt who is baptized at the
Jordan and then goes into the Wilderness
not for 40 years but for
days he has gone into the
Wilderness now what did we just identify
that Wilderness as in the Old
Testament that Wilderness we saw was a
symbol of the Valley of the shadow of
death Jeremiah 2:6 so my question
is what is Jesus where is Jesus going
when he enters Into the Wilderness what
is he doing
beloved he is walking on our behalf
through
something can y'all put in the chat for
me what is he walking through on our
behalf he is walking through the valley
of the shadow of death in fact in
fact let me break the psalm down again
for you I want you to note this remember
remember Psalm 23 verse one let's go to
the screen the Lord is my shepherd I
shall not want now what does a Shepherd
do what does a Shepherd do a Shepherd
leads the Sheep a Shepherd has
sheep well that's so interesting because
you'll remember that at the Jordan
notice with me on the screen
John the Baptist says this of Jesus the
next day John sees Jesus coming unto him
and sayi
Behold the Lamb of God which take takes
away the sin of the world Jesus is
identified as the lamb if Jesus is the
Lamb who is the Shepherd that is leading
him come on y'all if Jesus is here
identified as the lamb then Beloved the
shepherd the one leading him is his
father the Lord is my shepherd I shall
not want watch this go with me to the
next verse he maketh me the L on and
Green Pastures he leadth me beside Still
Waters interesting where is Jesus at the
time that John identifies him then Jesus
coming from Galilee to Jordan onto John
to be what baptized of
him it's almost as if beloved this Psalm
on a deeper level is walking us through
the experience of Jesus
he is the Lamb his father his Shepherd
is leading him he leads him beside Still
Waters meaning he's taking him into the
waters to be baptized and now now notice
the next vers in fact notice Matthew
3:16 the Bible says here and Jesus when
he was baptized went up straight way out
of the water and lo the heavens were
open unto him and he saw the spirit of
God descending like a dove upon him and
lighting upon him and a voice from
heaven saying this is my beloved Son in
whom I'm well
pleased watch this watch the next verse
Psalm 23 he restoreth my soul he leadth
me he leadth me in the paths of
righteousness for his name's sake so let
me ask you a question after Jesus is
baptized verse two is he then LED come
on y'all is Jesus led somewhere after he
is baptized is he he led somewhere for
righteousness
sake remember he's just said to John the
Baptist John the Baptist saying am I to
baptize you he says yes this is for the
sake of righteousness and right after he
is baptized right after he is baptized
we read these words in Matthew 4:1 then
was Jesus led up of the spirit Into the
Wilderness to be tempted of the
devil
he restoreth my soul he leadth me in the
paths of righteousness for his name's
sake Jesus is led by the spirit Into the
Wilderness into now watch the next verse
y'all come
on watch the next verse verse four Psalm
23:4 yay though I walk through the
valley of the shadow of death I will
fear no evil for thou art with me thy
rod and thy staff they comfort me you
understand beloved that Jesus after he's
identified as the Lamb of God and his
father is the shepherd after his father
leads him by Still Waters to be baptized
after the spirit comes upon him to lead
him into the paths of righteousness
after all that he now spends 40 days in
the wilderness or what we might now
identify as the
Valley of the sh
of death now please not beloved because
for many of us we think that when we
walk through the valley of the shadow of
death that means you're on your deathbed
you're about to die but the what we're
seeing here beloved is that there is a
walk through the valley of the shadow of
death that God's people must experience
and very often it has nothing to do with
actually dying like oh I'm at the end of
my life I'm walking through the Val no
no no no no this Valley of death beloved
I I I need y'all to catch
this Jesus is walking through the valley
of the shadow of death because he wants
to teach us something now now note with
me what's the next verse this is so
powerful y'all what is the next verse in
the psalm note with me Psalm 23 vers
verse 5 thou preparest a table before me
in the presence of my enemy thou
anointest my head with oil my cup
runneth over so now you remember that
Jesus is in the wilderness and he's got
no food
however
however there is a table that has been
set for him in the
wilderness did y'all catch
this there is a table that has been set
for him in the wilderness now you say
Pastor what table well listen come with
me to Deuteronomy chapter 8 Deuteronomy
chapter 8:2 notice what the Bible says
here and thou shalt remember all the way
which the Lord thy God LED thee 40 years
in the wilderness to Humble thee and to
prove thee and to know what was in thine
heart that thou whether thou would keep
his Commandments or no watch this next
verse and he humbled thee and suffered
thee to hunger and fed thee with
Mana which thou knowest not neither did
their fathers know that he might make
thee know that
man does not
live man does not live by bread only but
by every word that proceedeth out of the
mouth of the Lord doth Man live so the
Bible is telling us here in the Old
Testament that God want the children of
Israel through the Wilderness through
the shadow of the valley listen y'all
and he fed the Mana so that they could
know man doesn't live by bread alone but
by every word that proceeds out of the
mouth of God and what is the y'all
remember where do y'all remember at
someplace else where that was said
that's right y'all that's right in the
wilderness come with me to the screen
Luke 4:2 being
fasted being 40 days tempted of the
devil and in those days he did eat
nothing and they were and when they were
when they were ended he afterward
hungered and the devil said unto him if
thou be the Son of God command this
stone that it be made bread and Jesus
answering said it is written that man
shall not live by bread alone but by
every word that proceeds out of the
mouth of God so beloved yes to Kora this
is what I need you to
understand we all are in the Valley of
the shadow of
death the value of the shadow of death
is not an experience that someone
experienced at the end of their life or
if they're about no the the Valley of
the shadow of death is
now but the problem is many of us don't
live like that many of us don't realize
that so so so we we don't understand why
Jesus starts his ministry in this way
why does he begin why does he begin his
ministry in the Valley of the shadow of
death why is he starting here the answer
is profound in Hebrews chap 2:14 for as
much then as the children are partakers
of Flesh and Blood he also himself
likewise took part of the same that
through death he might destroy him that
had the power of death that is the devil
and deliver them who through fear of
death were all their lifetime subject to
bondage did y'all catch that just
now it was through the fear of death
Jesus comes to this earth to conquer
death he conquers he takes on flesh and
he's coming to conquer death which is
why he starts his ministry in the by a
40-day walk through the valley of the
shadow of
death again why is he beginning in this
symbolic Valley of the shadow of death
let's go to the screen again Matthew
chapter 3
and verse 16 the Bible says and Jesus
when he was baptized went up straight
way and out of the water and lo the
heavens were open unto him and he saw
the spirit of God descending like a dove
and note this y'all and lighting upon
Him lighting upon him let me tell you
you lighting upon Him means that Jesus
has now been lit up he has been lit up
he has been
lit
up the Holy Spirit descending on
him lights him
up Hebrews chap 2:14-15 for those of you
that are asking the the when the Holy
Spirit descended on him it light it was
lighting upon him now why is this
significant because where is he going
he's going into the valley of the shadow
of death
come on y'all he's going into the valley
of the shadow of death where there is
Darkness Jesus is coming to lighten your
Valley let me say it again beloved Jesus
came to this earth to lighten the Valley
of the shadow of death notice with me ma
Matthew 4:16 and the people with sat in
darkness saw great light and to them
which sat in the region and shadow of
death light is sprung
up Jesus came into this world as the
light of the world and he begins his
ministry in the Valley of the shadow of
death where humankind all humankind is
represented as trapped in this Valley of
the shadow of death this is why the
Bible says in Amos 5:8 seek him that
maketh the Seven Stars and Orion and
turneth the shadow of death into into
the morning and maketh the day the day
dark with night that calleth the Waters
of the sea and pour them out upon the
face of the waters the Lord is his name
Beloved the Lord the Lord is coming to
turn the shadow of death into morning
so now the question becomes what was the
light that he was to show those dwelling
in the in the shadow of death in other
words okay so everybody's in the Valley
of the shadow of death whether they
realize it or not Jesus is coming into
the Wilderness as the light of the world
but what does he want them to see in
this light what does he want them to
behold in the
wilderness what does he want those who
are in the Valley of the shadow of death
to behold how does he want them how is
he trying to to to to bring peace to
them oh the text says thy rod and thy
staff that's what the text
said yay do I walk through the valley of
the shadow of death I will fear no evil
why because thy rod and thy
staff they comfort
me they comfort me John 12:32 note it
with me John
12:32 Jesus said this and
I if I be lifted up from the
earth will draw all men unto me this he
said signifying what death he should die
yes
Latasha yes
Latasha the rod and the staff that
Comforts us is the Cross of Christ
that's why ooh ooh ooh that's why that's
why he comes into the valley of the
shadow of death and listen remember
remember what he said in John 3:14 as
Moses listen watch read it yourself and
as Moses lifted up the serpent
where
where where did Moses lift up the
serpent he lifted him up in the
wilderness
even so must the son of man be lifted up
beloved I need you to understand there's
a reason the serpent was lifted in the
wilderness there's a reason the serpent
was lifted in the Valley of the shadow
of death
y'all note with me note with me this is
the Bible in basic English and the Lord
said to Moses make an image of a
snake and put it on a rod and anyone who
has been wounded oh man
put it on a rod thy rod and thy staff
they comfort me how about Brenton's the
mo Moses said to the Lord or Moses
prayed to the Lord for the people and
the Lord said to Moses make the a
serpent and put it on a signal
staff thy
rod thy
staff the serpent on the pole the
sacrifice of Christ this is what
comforts me as I am on my journey
through the valley of the shadow of
death this is why Jesus said listen this
is why Jesus said in Luke Chapter 9:23
he said to them all if any man will come
after me let him deny himself and take
up take up the rod take take up the
staff come and follow
me take up the rod take up the staff in
other words I need you to behold me yes
Clint I love that because when the sea
opened up it was as if it created this
Valley which the children of Israel
could walk through what God is telling
us by this s story of the staff in the
wilderness which represented Christ and
him lifted up Christ crucified is that
in order for us to walk through the
valley many people are going to walk
into the valley but God says I want you
to walk through the
valley to walk through the valley means
you're coming out on the other side
you're going to be all right yay though
I walk through not into
through so why does God why then is is
Jesus trying to get us to look at the
serpent well what I need you to
understand Beloved the purpose of us
beholding the Savior on the cross in the
wilderness is because listen listen
listen God wants us to exp to understand
the experience that Jesus went through
on our
behalf if I can put it this way let's
let's go to the the screen notice with
me Zechariah
12:10 Zechariah 12:10 here's what the
Bible literally says y'all and I will
pour upon the House of David and upon
the inhabitants of Jerusalem the spirit
of Grace and
supplication and they shall look upon me
whom they have pierced and they shall
mourn for him as one mourneth for his
only son and shall be in bitterness for
him as one that is in bitterness for his
first born wait a
minute so God says that I want to give
you the spirit of Supplication now what
is a spirit what is supplication put it
in the chat for me please what is
supplication what is supplication
another word
for
supplication is
prayer so God says I'm going to pour out
upon you the spirit of Supplication or
prayer which is going to lead you to
look
upon the serpent on the pole the pierced
savior which as we are looking at him in
prayer something is supposed to happen
where we start
Mourning
are y'all catching this God wants us to
mourn now why would we be
mourning it it would almost be like uh
uh we're we're supposed to mourn
bitterly well why would we end up
mourning bitterly well let me show you
why notice with me Matthew chapter 26
this is a good example Matthew
26:75 and Peter remembered the words of
Jesus which he had said unto him before
the the cockro Thou shalt deny me Thrice
and he went out and
wept
mourned
bitterly it was Peter's rejection of
Christ that led him to This Bitter
experience this mourning
experience Peter realized his own s
sinfulness his own wickedness which led
him to weep
bitterly you see beloved it is as we
behold the sufferings of Christ watch
this in Isaiah 53 the Bible says he is
despised and rejected of men a Man of
Sorrows and acquainted with grief and we
hid as it were our faces from him he was
despised and we esteem them not surely
he has borne our griefs and carried our
sorrows yet we did did esteem him
stricken smitten of God and Afflicted
when we look at
Jesus as we behold the serpent on the
pole we get this immense picture of
suffering and that suffering we now we
begin to see that suffering happened
because of
me and now we begin to weep and if if
we're allowing the spirit to work in us
we begin to weep not only because of
what what our sins have done but because
they did it to him and what they did to
him and we begin to
mourn we begin to
grieve as we watch the sufferings of
Christ and the Bible says by beholding
we become changed we begin to
suffer with him which is interesting
because Peter writes this he says in 1
Peter chap 2: 211 he says for here unto
were you called because Christ also
suffered for us leaving us an example
that you should follow in his steps whoa
wait a
minute so so the reason Jesus comes
begins his ministry in the Valley of the
shadow of death is so that we can watch
his suffering in we can take our eyes
off of our sufferings oh man things are
going real bad for me we can take our
eyes off of our suffering and experience
the highest form the deepest form the
most Divine form of suffering there is
in existence which is the sufferings of
Christ look at the serpent on the pole
don't look at the bites on you don't
look at the serpent on the ground look
at the serpent on the pole why is he
trying to get us to focus on the
sufferings of Christ notice again with
me Hebrews chap
2:10 for it became him to make the
captains of their Sal the captain of
their salvation perfect through what
suffering 1 Peter chap 1:1 searching
what or what manner of time the spirit
of Christ which which in them did
signify when it testified beforehand the
sufferings of Christ 1 Peter 4:13 but
rejoice in as much as you are partakers
of
Christ's
suffering oh come on y'all come on
Listen First Peter chapter why why watch
this 1 Peter chapter 4:1 for as much
then as Christ has suffered for us in
the flesh arm yourselves likewise with
the same mind for he that has suffered
In the Flesh has ceased from sin hold on
a
second hold on
Pastor you mean to tell
me that if I
focus and really really train my mind to
focus on the the the sufferings of
Christ I will be so
overwhelmed with
grief that sin no longer looks
appealing I will be so overwhelmed with
with my own
wickedness and his righteousness I will
be so blown away by what he did that the
things that used to be much joy for me
in the world will cease and not because
I'm like I don't want to have joy in
that anymore but just simply looking at
you and gazing at you and understanding
your sufferings and then
experiencing those sufferings for myself
will will make the things of this world
grow strangely dim ah yes this is why
the Bible says in Philippians 2:5 let
this mind be in you which was also in
Christ Jesus who being in the form of
God thought it not robbery to be equal
with God but made himself of no
reputation and took upon him the form of
a
servant and was made in the likeness of
men and being found and fashion as a man
he humbled himself and became obedient
unto death even the death of the cro
whoo so hold
on Jesus spent 40 days walking through
the valley of the shadow of death going
through every possible experience mental
anguish pain that human beings have
experienced and he overcame that in our
behalf it was a symbol of him dying on
the cross for us and now now he's saying
listen beloved you too must walk through
this
Valley not sit in the valley not hang
out in the valley you must walk if you
want to make it out of the valley you've
got to follow take up your cross and
follow me behold
me this is why it tells us beloved in
Philippians
3:10 that I may know him and the power
of his resurrection
and the fellowship of his
sufferings being made conformable unto
his death now why would God want us to
recognize the sufferings of Christ why
does God want us to meditate upon it
until we enter into its Fellowship by
the way let me just give you the appeal
right now the appeal right now is this
the appeal right now is this would you
be willing to spend the next 40 days
days meditating on the serpent on the
pole would you be willing to enter into
the valley to enter into that experience
starting tonight I will put the link up
starting tonight Pastor starting tonight
there is a group of us who are going to
to to
daily
meditate
focus on the Lamb of God focus on the
serpent of Paul we're not going to ask
for stuff we're not going to pray you
can do that in your prayer time but in
this meditation time we are going to
strictly we're going to be quiet we're
just going to sit there and we're just
going to listen personally in our own
spaces and we're going to come together
at the end of those evening and we're
going to start sharing hey here's what I
saw today as I was meditating upon the
cross of Christ here's what I learned
listen y'all listen that's the appeal
but I still haven't told you like I'm l
hang out for you why you should do this
why you should walk through this Valley
why you should experience this 40-day
experience but we got to keep going on
because there's a reason why God wants
us to recognize why he wants us to
meditate why he wants us to see the lamb
let me show you the reason in Isaiah
chapter 6 verse1 The Bible says
this in the year that King Uzziah died I
saw also the Lord sitting upon a throne
high and lifted up and his train filled
the temple above it stood the seraphim
each one had six wings with Twain he
covered his faith and with Twain he
covered his feet and with Twain he did
fly and one Cried unto us unto another
saying holy holy holy is the Lord of
hosts the whole earth is full of his
glory and the post of the door moved at
the voice of him that cried and the
house was filled with with smoke and now
watch
this after
Isaiah catches an
unveiled Glimpse at Adam Patel I hope
you're
watching Adam I hope you're watching
after Isaiah catches an
unveiled glimpse of the glory of God
here is what he
says in verse five woe is
me for I am
undone because I'm a man of unclean lips
and I dwell in the midst of a people of
unclean lips for mine eyes have SE seen
the king the Lord of hosts I need y'all
to understand beloved that when we truly
see Christ on the
cross when the veil is removed from our
when when we by faith Focus the
spiritual eyes on the serpent on the
pole and by faith we Pierce the Veil we
see the glory of God and some something
happens we become undone we realize how
Wicked and sinful we are now watch this
y'all note this NE note this next
statement watch
this in the light of this matchless
Radiance this is review in Herald
October 15th 1888 in the light of this
matchless Radiance that made manifest
all he could bear in the revelation of
the Divine character his own talking
about Isaiah his own inward defilement
stood up before him with startling
clearness his very words seemed vile to
him thus when the servant of God is
permitted to behold the glory of the god
of heaven and he is unveiled to humanity
and realizes to a slight degree the
purity of the Holy One of Israel he will
make startling confessions of the
pollution of his soul rather than proud
boasts of his Holiness let me keep
reading you y'all let me keep reading
this is not the voluntary humility and
servile self approach that many seem to
consider a virtue to display this vague
mockery of humility is prompted by
Hearts full of Pride and self-esteem
there are many who demerit themselves in
word who would be disappointed if this
course did not call forth expressions of
praise and appreciation from others but
the conviction of the prophet was
genuine all
right
listen the reason why why God wants us
to behold the serpent on the pole is
because if we Behold Him with Clear
Sight if we stay long enough to Behold
Him we will realize just how wretched
our situation is and beloved when you
realize how wretched your situ when you
really really really realize just how
wretched your situation is Everything
Changes the world changes around you
everything changes around you life
becomes
different and the problem is many of us
are living life like because we have not
really stayed focused on Christ to
realize just how wretched our situation
is what is justification by faith this
is from the faith I live by Page
111 what is justification by faith it is
the work of God in laying the glory of
man in the dust and doing for man that
which is it is not in his power to do
for himself when men see their own
nothingness they are prepared to be
clothed with the righteousness of Christ
now listen to me you can say all day
today like uh you know oh I am wretched
wo is you can say all of
that and it's coming from from a sinful
heart that doesn't really understand the
gravity of what a genuine conviction oh
how wretched I am really what that
really means and the only way you can
get that conviction beloved is not by
just coming to the conclusion hey you
know what I think I'm pretty wretched no
no no no no no no that conclusion can
only come from beholding
the Lamb of God with unveiled
view this is why this is why it's said
in Philippians 3:9 look at the text and
being found not having my own
righteousness which is of the law but
that which is by faith through Christ
the righteousness which is of god by
faith that I may know him and the power
of his resurrection and the fellowship
of his suffering be made conformable
unto his death if by any means I might
attain unto the resurrection of the
Dead are y'all catching this no follow
me follow me Mark chapter 2:1 17 note
what the Bible says when Jesus heard it
he said unto
them they that are whole have no need of
a physician but they that are sick I
came not to call the righteous but
Sinners to repentance so watch this God
is trying to get us to behold the the
serpent on the pole so that we could
mourn and realize just how sick we
really are and if we realize that we are
sick if we realize that oh man like oh I
am mourning beloved listen to me this is
a Divine mourning that God is calling
for and the question becomes why does
God want us to mourn how many of you
would like to know why God wants us to
mourn why would God want us to
mourn put a one in the chat if you would
like to know and I got the text for you
right here I got the text for you right
here why does God want you to mourn why
does God want us to grieve in this
particular way why why why let me tell
you why Matthew Chapter 5 and verse four
Matthew Chapter 5 and verse four
the Bible
says
blessed are
they that
mourn for
they shall be
what what shall they
be what shall they be
everyone those who
mourn shall
be comforted
Comfort Comfort is a state of physical
ease or Freedom From Pain or
constraint or the easing or alleviation
of a person's feelings of greas grief
and
distress God wants to comfort
us this is why Isaiah 51:3 says the Lord
shall Comfort Zion he will Comfort all
her waste places he will make her
Wilderness like
Eden and her desert like the garden of
the Lord and joy and gladness shall be
found therein Thanksgiving and the voice
of Melody so God is trying to change the
Valley of the shadow of death so while
we're walking through the valley of the
shadow of death he says if you behold me
if you focus on the serpent in the
wilderness the serpent on the pole in
the wilderness I will turn your Valley
your desert into an
Eden your
mourning shall be turned into
Comfort Isaiah 40:1 Comfort ye my people
say the Lord your God
listen speak comfortably to Jerusalem
and cry unto
her that her Warfare is accomplished
that her iniquity is paron
how does our iniquity get pardoned look
at the lamb look at the lamb look at the
lamb that her iniquity is pardoned for
she has received of the Lord double for
all her sins watch this the voice of him
that crith in the wilderness the voice
of him that crith in the wilderness
prepare ye the way of the Lord make
straight in the desert a highway for our
God
every every Valley shall be exalt
exalted and every mountain and Hill
shall be made low the Crooked shall be
made straight and the rough places plain
and the glory of the Lord shall be
revealed and All Flesh shall see it
together the glory of the Lord beloved
shall be seen in the wilderness in the
desert God prepared a way in the
desert behold my rod and my staff are
with you they will comfort you
you I'm going to show you my glory and
what is that Glory John 17:5 and now oh
Father this is Jesus speaking just
before he dies and now oh Father glorify
thou me with thine own self with the
glory which I had with thee before the
world was the glory of the Lord is what
he did for us on Calvary it is the cross
it is the serpent on the pole by
beholding the glory imagine what would
happen to you if you sp spent 40 days
beholding the
glory not asking for
Stuff simply
beholding the
glory now now now I need I got to come
back to why does the Lord want us to
mourn so check this out remember the
Lord wants us to mourn because he's
trying to comfort us well note what
Jesus said in John 14:25 and now these
things these things have I spoken unto
you being yet present with you but the
comforter you can take this off the
screen right
now you can take it off the
screen come on
y'all the
comforter why does God want us to
mourn why does he want us to mourn over
the death of the
sun because when we see we're many of us
spend our time mourning our own wounds
mourning oh I didn't get that girl oh I
didn't get that guy oh I didn't get that
job we're mourning everything
else God says I need you to mourn the
death of my son on your behalf and those
who mourn the death of his son those who
mourn shall be comforted by the
comforter how do you get the comforter
they that are sick know that they need a
physician but they that are whole I'm
good I saw Jesus I'm good I got
it the human heart the carnal heart does
not know what it means to so you got you
got to take that all right we are going
to behold no no no no no you're not
doing anything else heart we're going to
Behold the Lamb of God every day if it
takes me 40 days if it takes me 80 days
if it takes me a 100 days help me to
Behold the Lamb of God because I know
that if I'm comforted by the by the by
the by the comforter then all these
other issues I'm dealing with mental
stress
depression anger all those other things
are going to be healed but if I'm if I'm
if I'm focusing on my wounds heal me
from my this heal me from that he God
says no I need you to focus on the
serpent on the pole and I will take care
of everything else I will when the
comforter comes beloved he takes care of
everything but he's not coming if you're
not mourning if you're not mourning why
do you need
comfort come on y'all if you're not
mourning why do you need Comfort the
highest form of mourning is in the
sufferings of Christ and when we learn
to enter into it by meditating upon that
by setting aside time every day all
right here I go here I go everything off
no distractions and I am going to Simply
Behold the Lamb of God simply behold the
serpent on the pole and as I am watching
this this suffering as I am watching the
death of Christ something happens self
dies because by beholding death we
become changed
in self dies
y'all so let me tell you what our
problem
is I got to say this
carefully we were never commanded to
kill
ourselves let me just take a SI
we were never commanded to kill
ourselves you can't kill
self but that's what many of us have
been doing in our Christian experience
I'm going to kill self I'm going to I'm
going to put self to death no Beloved
the way that self dies is by beholding
the lamb
when we behold his sufferings we die
with him and it's a natural
death but many of us have been spending
our time trying to subdue self without
looking to Jesus so in essence we're
basically trying to kill
ourselves and God never God called us to
look it is B let me here's how Ellen
White puts it let me let me put this up
Christ object lessons page
159 Christ object lessons page 159 note
what it says
here no man can empty himself of self we
can only cons we can only consent for
Christ to accomplish the work the
language of the soul will then be Lord
take my heart for I cannot give it it is
thy property keep it pure for I cannot
keep it for thee save me in spire myself
my weak un Christlike self mold me
fashion me raise me into a pure and holy
atmosphere where the rich current of thy
love can flow through my soul you can't
kill self
y'all all you can do is bring self to
the cross and hold his head and go look
n no no we are staying here and we are
looking until you
die
the Bible tells us but if the spirit of
him that raised up Jesus from the dead
dwell in you he that raised up Christ
from the dead shall also Quicken your
mortal bodies by his spirit that
dwelleth in you the reason Jesus wants
us to behold his sacrifice on the cross
is so that by beholding the spirit
enters into us the spirit becomes to
comfort us because we are truly mourning
how unlike we are to
Jesus
this is why this is why Paul says I
protest by your rejoicing which I have
in Christ Jesus our lord I Die daily
Jesus said I need to pick up your cross
daily and walk with me through the
valley daily I need you to behold me
daily and why why because listen Beloved
the sufferings ultimately lead to Glory
let me show it to you Romans 88:18 the
Bible says for I reckon that the
sufferings of of of this present time
are not worthy to be compared with the
glory which shall be revealed in US
Hebrews 2:10 for it became him for whom
are all things and by whom are all
things in bringing many sons unto glory
to make the captain of their salvation
perfect through suffering 1 Peter 1:11
searching what or or what matter of time
the spirit of Christ which was in them
did signify when it testified before the
sufferings of Christ and the glory that
should
follow this is why the Bible says in 1
Peter 4:12 beloved thinking not strange
concerning the fiery remember those
fiery serpents thinking not strange
concerning the fiery trials which is to
try you as though some strange thing
happened onto you but rejoice in as much
as you are partakers of Christ
sufferings that when his glory shall be
revealed you may be glad also with
exceeding Joy all right y'all okay we
are almost there we're almost done I
need y'all to really focus in here I I
need you to really focus in here listen
listen
um okay
okay do y'all remember when Moses was in
the wilderness for 40 days and something
happened something special happened to
him do y'all remember that you you
remember right I think yall remember let
me show you something The Exodus 34:28
go to the screen Exodus
34:28 and he was there with the Lord 40
days in 40 nights and he did neither eat
bread nor drink water
H and he wrote upon the tables of the
word the tables the words of the
Covenant The Ten Commandments let me ask
you a question y'all let me ask you a
question come
back where were the Ten Commandments
written and what time period were they
written where were they written and
during
what
they were written in the
wilderness they were W written during a
40 day period beloved listen to me
listen to
me how would you like to go into the
Wilderness for 40 days to experience
Jesus in a way you may have never
experienced him before and while you are
there in the wilderness with Jesus for
40 days just beholding the glory of the
Lord the holy spirit is writing on your
heart his
law Not only was the law written during
this 40-day period but watch this watch
this come with me in Exodus the very
next verse the very next verse H Exodus
34:29 and it came to pass when Moses
came down from the mount from Mount Si
with the two tables of stone in Moses
hand the
law when he came down from the mount
that Moses knew not that's what the
whisked not it means he knew not that
his skin of his face Shone while he talk
listen to me
[Music]
y'all wow wow W Moses came down not
realizing how much he had changed he
didn't see it because he was just
focused on God he wasn't looking at
himself he wasn't like man look at my
face right now he was so focused on the
on on the glory of God that when he
comes down everybody else saw it yo
what's been happening with you over
these last couple of days and weeks and
months and you look different what's
been happening with
you H how people other people saw
it Moses was just like what
huh he wasn't looking at himself he
wasn't looking at his own face he wasn't
looking at the glory that came upon him
he was busy beholding the glory of
God see there's a
veil there's a veil that many of God's
people you know in the Old Testament
there was a veil in the temple and on
that Veil were angels and all kind of
things well for for us beloved there's a
veil and on that Veil is all kinds of
stuff in the world that is designed to
block our eyes from beholding to take
away our time from beholding Jesus so
because we cannot see the lamb we are
walking around with this manufactured
righteousness with this manufactured
mourning oh wo is me we don't really
understand what it means to enter into
the sufferings of Christ but if if we
decide okay
Lord I am going to focus on you like I
have never done before I'm going to take
these next 40 days and I'm going to
spend half an hour an hour an hour and a
half two whatever it takes and I'm G I'm
not no not 10 minutes I can do that in
prayer time I need to set time it would
be
well for us to spend a thoughtful
hour every day meditating upon the life
of of Christ from the manger to the
cross
and allow the imagination to grasp each
scene
especially the closing ones you see
beloved we listen we are out there
manufacturing righteousness we're out
there trying to
do when Jesus is saying if you would
only look at me if you would Pierce if
you would allow your faith to pierce
through the veil and behold me you are
going to have a shocking revelation of
yourself and your own filthiness you're
going to mourn you're going to go into a
period of grieving where you realize
just how sinful and wretched you are and
and and and and you are not afraid of
your own self and you're wondering God
can you even deliver me that's how
sinful and wretched I am you you begin
to feel this and then the comforter
begins to say now just focus I'm going
to comfort you I'm going to comfort you
I'm going to strengthen you I'm going to
comfort you I'm going to write while
you're while you're here with me locked
in the Wilderness while you're here I'm
going to write on your heart and I'm
going to the the glory of God is going
to be seen upon you but I need you to
just free I need you to look I need you
to focus listen to me y'all listen
listen come on we are almost there we
are almost there I got three more
verses 2 Corinthians 2 Corinthians
chapter 3 2 Corinthians chapter 3
nevertheless when it shall turn to the
Lord the veil shall be taken away now
the Lord is that spirit and where the
spirit of the Lord is there is Liberty
but we are with open face not veiled
face but open face beholding as in a
glass the glory of the Lord are changed
into the same image from glory to glory
even as by the spirit of the
Lord sister white comment on this says
this we all with open face beholding as
in a glass the glory of the Lord are
changed into the same image from glory
to glory even as by the spirit of the
lord we are to keep the Lord ever before
us those who do this walk with God as
did Enoch and imperceptibly to
themselves they become one with the
father and with the
son day by day A change is wrought upon
mind and hearts and the natural
inclinations the natural ways are molded
after God's ways and spirit they
increase in spiritual knowledge and grow
up into the full stature of men and
women in Christ Jesus they reflect to
the world the character of Christ and
abiding in him and he in them they
fulfill the mission for which they have
called they were called to be the
children of God they
become the light of the
world a city that is set up on a hill
cannot be hid no man when he lith a
candle covered with a vessel and put it
under a bed but set it on a Candlestick
that they may enter in that they which
enter in may see the light those who
have been lighted from above send forth
the bright beams of the sun of
righteousness they those who have been
lighted from above send forth the bright
beans of the son of righteousness how
did they get lighted from above because
they were looking up to the Cross they
were looking at
Jesus
so
so Galatians 2:20 20 I got this and one
more verse for you and then the appeal
Galatians 2:20 the Bible says I am
crucified with
Christ I am crucified with
Christ nevertheless I live yet not I but
Christ liveth in me and the life which I
I live which I now live in the flesh I
live by the faith of the Son of God who
loved me and gave himself for me you see
what happens when we behold when we
Behold the Lamb of God when we behold
the Lamb of God that takes away the sin
of the world this is our last
Slide the next day John seeth Jesus
coming unto him and saith
behold behold the lamb of God which
takes away the sin of the world beloved
when we Behold the
Lamb death to self becomes a natural
process we're not forcing self to die
we're not trying to kill
ourselves by simply beholding the
lamb
uninterrupted
focused we begin to see the
glory and the the the glory makes us
mourn and when we mourn this the
comforter can then come and do his
work and as he Comforts us and fills us
with himself because he sees that we are
grieving a righteous grieving a
righteous mourning he now knows this is
the work is happening in you and as we
are beholding the lamb our light our
faces begin to shine as he's writing the
law of God in our hearts while we are in
the wilderness and beloved this this is
the process so here is my appeal here is
my
appeal right now on Mighty networks
we've just set
up this page this group group and I'm
inviting
you I'm inviting
you to begin today is day one I'm
inviting you to say okay I'm going to
commit to spending time every
day
meditating on the serpent on the
pole and at the you do it at your if you
want to do it in the morning you can do
it in the afternoon you can do it night
but at the end of every evening I just
want you to come to the page and say hey
man as I was meditating on the Ser this
is what I saw today and what what we're
going to do is we're going to create
like this Collective Journal of our
40-day journey of what the Lord showed
each one of
us as we took time to
meditate on
Jesus so we're going to put the link in
the chat right now hopefully it's going
to go in the chat right now this is my
special appeal this is everything I was
building up to in this sermon are you in
40 days Lord I need you to change me I'm
tired of trying to change
myself I'm tired of bringing my issues
and my look at my wound here and look at
my wound there and not looking at
you Lord I got a thousand
wounds but what you're telling me is
that if I look at you the comforter will
come and will take care of everything
that needs to be taken care of in me
Will Comfort me will strengthen me to
endure we do all those things then Lord
please help me to just look at you so if
you're in I see people saying I'm in I'm
in I want you to put that in the chat
I'm in I'm in put that in the chat I'm
in I'm in and if you're in let we're
going to put the link in the chat if you
don't see the link in the chat we'll put
it up uh uh uh in the description of
this video once it's up but we're going
to I need to get this link in the chat
so if if you guys team if you can put
that link in the chat right now um it's
the link that I text you this morning
all right there's a lot of amins there
it is just keep dropping it in the chat
for me please cuz people are going to
miss it people are going to miss it I'm
in so beloved listen let me break it
down for you again very simply you are
going to take time and listen y'all I'm
not talking about 10 minutes I'm not
talking about I need you to set aside
time to step into the presence of God
and to sense the presence of God and
you're going to say okay every day I'm
going to take time I'm not going to tell
you what time but you're going to take
significant time and all you're going to
do is
focus on the serpent on the
pole you can take another time to pray
and pray about this and pray about that
and lift other people in prayer but this
time is dedicated to being locked in the
wilderness with
Jesus and I'm going to behold and I'm
going to allow the spirit to speak to me
and you know what the spirit's going to
do the spirit's going to say hey look at
that right there hey look at this moment
you know what Jesus experienced as he
was on the cross saying my God my God
why is Thou forsaken me do you do you
understand that Jesus felt that he would
not be raised from the second this holy
spirit is going to be raised from Death
the holy spirit is going to show you I
don't know what he's going to show you
but he's going to show you things that
are going to change your
life so we're going to sit and we're
going to listen and at the end of it
when you're done just get on Mighty
networks hey guys I just want to tell
you here's my paragraph doesn't have to
be a dissertation here's my paragraph
This is what I found today and read what
other people are finding read what the
holy spirit is showing other people as
they focus and they see the depth of
this work Christ did for us on the
cross again I'm in I'm in I I'm going to
go over the mighty networks right now
after this is done and I want to see how
many of you are in right now we just
started the group yesterday there was
one person in there because I I did not
mention at all today I hope this thing
is
packed and I pray I pray that by the end
of the these 40 days you will be a
different person than you were going
into
this let's pray heavenly father thank
you for speaking to
us thank you for showing
us how Jesus and why he began his
ministry in the
wilderness as an example to
us Lord bless us as we Embark upon this
journey and change us
Lord that is our prayer change us not
according to our strength but according
to yours teach us to Behold the Lamb of
God in Jesus name we pray
amen